Nathaniel Pautzke 6142 Chaska Rd., Shorewood, MN 55331 (952) 688-8226

Nathaniel.Pautzke@gmail.com

Website: https://www.nathanielpautzke.com/resume

### SUMMARY

An enthusiastic Software Engineer with over four years of programming experience. Throughout my professional history, I have worked with scripting automation to large scaling frameworks. I had the opportunity to program with early languages similar to Cobol and Machine Assembly, to modern-day languages like Java, Ruby, and Python. Enjoy learning new languages, frameworks, and operating systems to cultivate the best solution for any problem.

### COMPUTER SKILLS

## Languages

- Proficient in: Java, SQL, HTML/HAML (paired with Thymeleaf Template Engine), CSS, and JavaScript
- Familiar with: Ruby, Python, Microsoft Visual Basic, ES5 and ES6 JavaScript, and Bash Scripting

### Frameworks

- Proficient in: Spring Boot and Spring MVC
- Familiar with: Rails, React.js, and Node.js

#### Testing

Junit (unit testing), JMeter (integration testing)

## Software

- Database: Microsoft SQL, Microsoft Access, and PostgreSQL
- Platforms: Microsoft Windows, Linux Ubuntu, CentOS
- Editors: IntelliJ Idea, RubyMine, Visual Studio Code, Vim

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Associate Software Engineer**

Feb. 2019-Present

### IDEMIA

- Adhere to Agile practices for a continuous integration environment
- Heavily document code, services, processes, and other useful items
- Leverage Spring Boot and Java to create RESTful backend services
- Understand maven build process to build complex applications
- Code various integration and unit tests to adhere to a strict line coverage percentage
- Knowledge of various secure code scan products to create dependable code
- Comprehend basic enterprise integration patterns and utilize Apache Camel
- Understanding of data cryptography libraries to perform optimized and secure data transmissions
- Utilize docker and docker-compose to aid in efficient deployment in conjunction with Kubernetes
- Work with software and various teams to recognize and remediate any potential security vulnerabilities (Example: Version Scans, Nessus, OWASP)
- · Designed and developed a full-stack testing solution utilized across multiple teams
- Familiarity through the entire build process from developing code to deploying in a sandbox environment for integration testing
- Experience as the role of Project Lead building design and product documentation for the development of a new product

## Data Engineer (title: Data Processing Tech I)

April 2016-Jan. 2019

IWCO Direct Summary:

Took raw data to be used for dynamic page content. Daily I work with various scripting languages to re-engineer data to normalize, cleanse, and append data to meet customer needs. Mostly I use TSSUtil which is a blend of COBOL, machine assembly, Basic and Linux shell scripting. Over my career, I have worked with over half a billion records for mailing. Another part of my role includes using software to create advanced matching for cleansing duplicate records in large files.

## Software Engineer Intern

May 2015 - Jan. 2016

Aglytix

Summary:

While adhering to Agile methodology and Scrum I worked on documentation and implementing features on the Rails framework. Sprint weeks consisted of creating HTML and JavaScript content to help customers navigate the software with ease. Basic testing, API integration, debugging, and Java backend reports were utilized.

### **PROJECTS**

## **Ruby on Rails**

 Created a dynamic webpage that consists of aspects of my life. A resume space, administrator login, photography page, and various other features. The project was developed on a Linux box using the RubyMine IDE. Purchasing my own domain, I was able to map my Heroku DNS to my custom domain name that also includes security certificates. You can find this project at https://www.nathanielpautzke.com/resume

### **EDUCATION**

## Colorado State University System, Global Campus

• Bachelor of Science, Information Technology

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# **TestOut Pro**

- TestOut Server Pro: Manage and Administer, Install and Configure and Testout Security Pro
- Familiar with CompTIA A+, Network+, Security+, Project+, and Microsoft Server 2016

# OTHER SKILLS

## Soft Skills

- Communication: Work with a cross-functional team daily. In my current role as a software
  engineer, we function as a global team. One team resides in Poland while another dwells
  in France. Most of our communication is done via email or process documents. Using
  quality communication is vital in a global team.
- Leadership: I have demonstrated leadership in acting as project lead on one of our emerging products. I had the opportunity to study our architecture and propose a solution to our product. Also, I oversaw leading daily standups with several teams including our regional project manager.
- Problem Solving: Daily I utilize problem-solving to complete tasks. As a software engineer, this skill is vital. I enjoy researching and learning new frameworks and languages to create the most efficient solution.